I can't remember how it exactly happened,
but I was using animation to generate my visuals
to start with. And then I was trying things with
anaglyphic 3-D, and trying to present
3-D visuals, and I then I was like, well,
could I control this 3-D environment live,
and display that and more generative visuals?
So things that are created directly from the music,
and the environment that music is in.
SI started out doing visuals in Manchester and
got more into coding because
I wanted to bring more interactivity into the visuals,
so I was playing around with things
like Quartz	Composer and Processing.
I knew my library inside-out, my library of clips,
and I wanted something that would be different
each time, but wouldn't mean generating new media each time.
And, just to keep it exciting for myself,
also I saw the benefits of how some of these
visuals look, especially when you start introducing
physics and all these sort of things,
and the audio-reactive side of it, and I guess through that
I started realizing there is a digital community out there,
who are working in creative code
and using code mainly because code had become far
more accessible, so it's more documented.
That community's made it more accessible.
Because, I remember trying when I was maybe
thirteen, fourteen, trying to get into code
and just driving myself crazy and not getting anywhere with it.
So it was, I gave myself about a ten year break and then had another look,
and it starts making more sense.
I think it's going to drive things along must faster,
I think there's going to be more varied output
the more people you work with.
So, ideas you'd never have come up with
on your own and problems that need
solving - that you can solve - that they made,
which could drive the creative process.
So I was installing all this stuff on my mom's work machine,
and trying to hack into my mate's computers and open their CD trays,
and all these sort of things.
I had to go to my mate's house,
install this little package on his machine,
and then I went home and just opened and shut
his CD tray.
And he came in the next day like,
you won't believe what's going on with my computer.
I was like, I will.
I don't know, sometimes some people think
they need to know this stuff, when really,
you might be better off sticking
with the more traditional side of it.
Because it's not an easy thing to start,
get going on it, especially with code inside of it.
It can put you back a couple of years,
I think. It's quite intense learning sometimes.
I think the advantage is with working wit
h other people who know different things already,
rather than trying to teach yourself -
which is something I'm guilty of - which is trying
to learn everything.
I'm quite keen on building open software
packages that can be picked up by non-technical people,
and taken to new areas that would never be expected.